Speaker 1: Thank you very much, Mr. Chair, and for your courtesy, Ranking Member Blumenthal. Thank all of you for being here. To all of the witnesses, I am so profoundly grateful for your leadership and your courage in revisiting some of the most painful moments
Speaker 2 (lower-pitched voice): of your life. All in order to help prevent others from enduring what you guys have endured. You are world-class athletes. You're heroes
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): and you're survivors.
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): Your bravery here today to share your stories deserves our gratitude and respect to be sure. But I just also want you to know what a change you are making for future generations of athletes as well as current athletes. And what a great example your standing
Speaker 2 (lower-pitched voice): up and speaking out is giving to so many other people who are going to also need to muster bravery and courage in their lives for one
Speaker 4: reason or the next.
Speaker 4: I just thought maybe each of you could take a minute to address two questions I have, which will likely take the rest of the time I have for questions. Given your experiences, I'd like to hear, if you can identify this, who you believe to be most responsible for allowing these abuses to continue.
Speaker 4: And, also, what cultural factors
Speaker 1: in your training fostered an atmosphere in which these abuses could begin and continue for so long? And maybe, Mr. Maurizzi,
I could start with you.
Speaker 5: Who would I hold accountable? Who do you think is the most,
I mean...
Speaker 6: Two answers come to my mind. First and foremost, when I decided to file a grievance,
I...
I hired
Speaker 6: an attorney to guide me through this. My attorney's first advice was to contact the local authorities and to report a crime. The statute of limitations had run way past, by the time I reported the
Speaker 7: crime, I was 36 years old. I believe at the time in Michigan where I was living, the statute was 26. I was also in New York and
the 26th
Speaker 7: was as old as I could be. I couldn't have fathomed of even
Speaker 6: dealing with that until much later, to be honest with you. That was one thing. Second thing are the the various rinks and figure skating clubs that I was a member of and participated in. My coach, I learned later, had to move from club to club
to club
Speaker 6: because allegations surfaced about his treatment of his athletes.
Speaker 9: But none of them shared with other rinks?
Speaker 6: They did.
Speaker 9: Oh, they did.
Speaker 6: They did share with other rinks. They shared the rumors that they heard. But difficult to prosecute somebody on rumors, I guess. So everybody...
Speaker 6: knew about it. For example, when Richard moved to the Detroit Skating Club, a former student of mine told me that she was told by the officials there that he wasn't allowed inside the men's locker room, but he still was hired.
Speaker 10: Okay. I don't want to interrupt any of you, but we have limited time, so
Speaker 1: I'm just wondering if Ms. Farrell and Ms. Weber and Andrew,
you can...
Speaker 1: to take a stab each at this?
Speaker 11: - Yeah, so in
Speaker 12: terms of who, I would say it really goes back to the men that are listed in the report that was given out. They knew about it. There was the same thing with the man that repeatedly molested me. He was known to be this person, but there was actually a report.
Speaker 11: And it was swept under the rug.
Speaker 11: and the culture that has to change, it's,
it's the
Speaker 12: idea that we are so brave to be here, is,
it solidifies
Speaker 12: what the problem is. That is what shows like how hard it is. - Right. - And then you're expecting,
A
Speaker 12: kid to come forward and say things that they do not know the words that exist for, right? So it's a culture, it's just a cultural issue, and it's the idea that people are finally speaking up. And even look at like Time Magazine, people are finally speaking up. Like, honestly, that's not true. We've been yelling, and no one's been listening. So
I would
Speaker 12: say the ears of all the adults out there.
Speaker 13: Thank you. Ms.
Speaker 14: Weber?
Yeah.
So
Speaker 15: when I think about who's most accountable, obviously, as I said, USA Gymnastics, USOC, Michigan State. But if you look a little bit deeper than
Speaker 16: that, I think it all started when the Carolis, who brought USA Gymnastics to where it is now, when they came over from Romania, they brought a lot of those training styles over and a lot of the abusive training styles. And I think that USA Gymnastics started to see that it was winning medals and they were getting lots of money and then as a result I think that that
training staff
Speaker 16: kind of seeped into the personal coaches across the nation. And now that's the normal way of coaching. And you can ask any elite gymnast, they know exactly which coaches across the country are the most abusive, but people will still send their athletes there, or their kids there, because they know they want to be successful, and that's their best chance of making the Olympic team. So that's what they've made us believe, that that's the only way you're going to...
Speaker 16: you're gonna win medals and be as successful as is um by having coaches that will beat you to the ground like that um so i think
the the
Speaker 16: cultural issues go you know
Speaker 17: start they start with the corolle's and in that training style
thank you and
Speaker 18: with the chair's indulgence could we hear briefly from ms dancer too thank
you uh as
Speaker 19: far as the most accountable i would obviously agree with jordan since very similar to my experience
Speaker 19: And with regard to how people say this, that I'm so brave and I appreciate what you say because I've never felt brave. I felt like I was doing the right thing. And so hearing Mr. Morizzi's testimony made me cry because that's one of the reasons why I came forward was to give,
to tell people
Speaker 19: it's okay to speak up. And the other thing is, I guess the cultural...
-
Speaker 19: Problems in gymnastics are, there's so many, as she said. Larry Nassar saw the coach's abuse, you know, almost on a daily basis and he didn't report their abuse and vice versa. So they protected each other and
Speaker 19: You know, I obviously want to come forward because I was sexually abused, and so I wanted to do the right thing, and I wanted to protect others, and it shouldn't take having to have the experience to do the right thing. Because I wonder if it, you know, if this would have happened to anyone that was running USAG, any one of their daughters or their sons or any of their kids, you know, would they react differently, you know?
Look, thank you
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): all very, very much.
And I
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): look forward to reading and hearing some more of your testimony. Thank you again to the Chair and Ranking Member for your courtesy.
Senator
Speaker 21: Blumenthal.